어떤 여자가자살하는 걸 봤어
근데 그애생긴게 꼭 나같더라엘리자베스 차일즈
누군지 알아보던지 안되면
남은 물건이라도털어와야지베스가 경찰이야
나 경찰이라고
망할 매기 첸은또 누구야?베스가 쏜 여자야
키아라의 양육권을되찾을 유일한 방법은니가 계속 있을 수 있다는걸
보여주는 거다
우린 복제인간이야누군가의 실험물이고
지금은 우릴 죽여버리고 있지!
독일애가 죽었어누가 쐈어
내 바로 눈 앞에서!
너 시체부터처리해야돼
베스 파트너가독일애를 찾았어..
일부분 말이야..시체가 나랑 일치하면
경찰에선 누군가
사진을 확인해 보겠고아마 베스나솔찍히 너꺼 밖에 없을꺼야
나야 이미 죽은걸로 되어있으니까
베스한테크게 모아둔 돈이..일종의 자금인데
우리가 공식적으로는
얻을 수 없는 정보를사려고 했던거야그 자금은
내가 낼 수 있는거였어
살인자가 아트한테접촉했어
벌써 카티야가 총맞은현장에 나가있어저격할 때
숨어있던 곳에 있었어
그래, 따끈한 껀 잡은거야전화 통화에, 증거들도 있고
"오묘하고 놀라워내 주님께 감사를 드립니다"
난 괜찮아! 가! 쫓아!
난 베스가 아니야!
"난 베스가 아니야"
쉬
한글자막 :  Nike Plus
왜 우리 중에 하나면서우릴 죽이는거지?뭐가 문제인거야?
입냄새에더럽게 미친거나에 대해 알아?
우리 애들은?
니가 그앨 바로우리 집 현관으로끌어들이지 않았단건
어떻게 알아?
그야 걔한테 철봉을 박아줬고나라면 안그럴테니까난 너보다
훨씬 오래동안
이런 악몽속에살았어, 사라나한텐 보호해야할
가족이 있다고 말했지
할 수 있는건다할꺼야
맞다. 재정지원도해줬고그치, 그래 베스가
가지고 있던 돈도 필요하고
네 보호비야
너가 맞아나 그돈 훔치려고 했었어
그리고 튈려고..근데 못하겠더라
나도 가족이 있거든앨리슨
내 딸
딸 있어?
그래, 이름은키아라야사실 오늘 그애 보기로
되있었는데
살인자가 내 꽁무니를쫓아다니잖아 그러니..잠깐, 생물학적으로
네 아이야..
아님 입양한거야우리 애들처럼?
내 아이지, 왜?
그런 얘기는 이전에 했었어야하는거 아니야?내가 왜
그랬어야 하는데?
지금 말을 하는건우리가 이일을처리해야 되서잖아, 그치?
베스는 살인자의 목록에 올라있었고지금은, 그게 나거든
그래? 거기서내가 뭘해야 되는데?
어떻게 도와줄까?
시간을 내줘
어떻게든너가 필요할꺼야
와우, 엄청나네이거 아주 오래된
손잡이에
새로 삽화를새긴거 같에물고기는 암컷이고
기호학적으로 얘기하면
오래 전에는 보편적으로다산을 뜻하는 거였지근데 이 날개들은
어쨌거나, 그게..
진짜로, 쟤 뭔 얘기야?
조용해원래 괴상한거뿐이야
미안, 먄 먄 먄알았어 얘기가 샛네
그애 안죽었으면
우리가 찾아야해뭘 알고 있는지 알아야지
너 미쳤어?살인광이란 말이야
그래, 그래도 그애가누군지 알아야해, 사라그애..
걔가 우릴 찾았잖아
해답을 가지고있다고그 방법이
딱 하나 있지
내가 다시 경찰로돌아가는거
안돼
절대 안돼. 너 베스로돌아가서는 안된다고죽은 경찰관
사칭하는건
그것도완전히 새로운 범죄거든솔직히 말하자면, 경찰들이랑
같이 있는게 제일 안전할꺼 같에
그게 정말 니 입으로할 소리야?
저기, 아트가이미 살인범을 찾고 있어
베스인척 하면서눈을 가리는거지그애한테 무슨 일이 생긴건지
사람들이 찾게 두는거야
그리고서그걸 알아내면내가 나서서
처리할 수 있을꺼야
"처리해"?
나 이제 미친 놈의 유전자가이해되기 시작한다
머, 그래,뇌내 나쁜 화학작용은
유전적일 수 있거든그래도 환경은..
그건 개인적이야, 그치?
내 말은, 바로 그것이천성과 양육 환경에 대한
모든 궁금증이라는 거지
좋아, 천성에 대해말하자면
지금까지, 9중에서
하나는 미친놈이고다른 넷을 죽였어하나는 자살했고
하나는 빌어먹을학부형 아줌마고
거다, 그쪽 너
내 미친 누나는 제정신이지..비교하자면고맙다, 피
내 생각엔이게 그애가 어디서 왔는지알아내는데 도움이 될꺼 같에
난 이쪽을 알아볼께
아, 경찰 일이다
아트가 증거를 찾았데알았어
저기, 너 이거 실수로라도앨리슨한테
보여준건 아니지, 그렇지?
장난해? 걔 자기 룰루레몬에 지려버릴껄(룰루레몬-고급요가복브렌드)
앨리슨은 대기시켜놨어
젬마 안전벨트확실히 매게해!
학교 가는 날 아침인데애들을 부모님댁에
보낸다고?
그래, 애들 자고올꺼야
그 대답이 아니잖아저기, 당신이 물어볼 처지가
아닐텐데, 그렇지, 도니?
그래, 왜?
왜 애들 일들을전부 취소한건데?내 자신을 위한 시간이
좀 필요하거든
당신도 목요일 밤마다 고객들이랑정기적으로 술마시잖아, 그치?
그래그럼 당신이
시끄럽게 들어오는게
보통 새벽 3시나 되야당신 보지
시끄럽게 않거든한번 그랬지
어, 젠장
미안
나도 조마조마하네
머리는 어때요?
아마 너랑 비슷할껄
살아있어서 좋은 날이지베스우리 애들도
너한테 고마워해
망할 전 마누라까지도너한테 고마워하지
예, 말도 꺼내지 마세요
나개 안그랬어사람들이 그랬지
너한테선물 하나 있다
우리 살인범이볼일보러 들렸거든놈의 오토바이고
놈을 잡았나요?
아니, 그래도 증인이 있어
피묻은 보도블럭만쫓아가면 돼
안녕, 걸어다니는상처투성이가 오셨네
대 괜찮아, 아트?그래
그래? 저기, 난 기쁘거든
우리가 놈을 잡을꺼테니걱정마, 알았지?너네 범인이 장갑을 꼈더라고
지문은 없어
그래도 놈이 흔적을감추지는 못했지가서 보라고
직접 수술했군
놈 뭐야, 군출신?
다친거처럼 보이지?
아, 증인이 준비됐어
아트, 선배가맡으시겠어요?
아니
가지
전 하나도모르고 잤어요
믿기지가 않네요
트레버가 제 방에 왔는데어두웠었는데
애가 완전히젖어있더라고요
피였죠
애 말로는화난 천사였데요
안녕, 트레버
아저씨한테 화난 천사가어떻게 생겼는지 말해주겠니?
욕실에 있던 사람이여자였어?
그럴 수 있어?
제가 얘기해 볼께요
그렇지 물론
괜찮단다, 얘야
난 다른 사람이야
아줌마가올꺼라고 했어요
색깔 골라보세요
빨강
빠-알-강
하나 고르세요
거기
잠깐 잠깐 잠깐내가 좀 볼께
내가 가져도 될까?네
뭐 좀 건졌어?
기념품이요
이건 또 뭐야?
이봐, 이거 좀담아주겠어?
끝났다, 아가야다 됐어
그래, 다시 말하지만8시야. 애 잠들기 전에
우리 엄마에요?아니다, 아가
방금 애한테저 아니라고 하신거에요?사라, 전화는 왜 한거니?
기대에도 불구하고네가 안나타나면, 정말..
우리 아직 계속하는건지만확실히 해주세요그래, 맞다, 일단은
예, 저 갈꺼에요
아이랑 얘기 좀 할께요?
저녁에 얘기하면 된다
아이를 실망시키면
끝이야, 다시는애 못보게 할꺼다
제가 간다고 말 했죠
그럼 다들 그 종이 접기의사본을 가지고 계시죠
목격자 말로는우리가 틀렸었다고 합니다..
피해자를 죽인건여성으로, 베스만한 몸집입니다
그 피해자에 대해선쉽지가 않네요
두개골을 재구성하는데
이게 자갈 부수는 기계를통과한 거라서.. 그래도사망 원인은
알아냈습니다
이 구멍은223구경입니다
그럼, 원거리에,고성능 무기라는걸 알았으니
여성 저격범이 지목됐던
살인사건 하나만말해보세요
프로파일은 어떤가?여성 살인자들은 만성적으로
분리되어있는 경향이 있습니다
고립은 인격장애를 낳죠여기 시편,
"이렇게 빚어진 것이 오묘하고 놀라워"
종교적 환상을 가지고있어요
막대 그림들이나인형 머리
종이접기까지..
유아기 발달 과정 문제?학대를 심하게 당했다던가요
예, 하지만 매우 조심스럽죠자기 나름대론요
지금까진아무런 지문도 없어어요그럼 DNA 증거는?
서두르고 있는데, 누군가 기록에일치하는게 있더라도아는데까지는
일주일은 걸릴꺼야
피해자 지문도건진게 없나?손에선 일치하는게
안나왔어?
아니, 아뇨, 없어요
주목해봐요. 중요한건우리가 지금
매우 계획적이고
게임을 즐기는여성 살인범을 쫓고 있다는거죠
이 종이접기처럼말이죠엔지
특정한 선택은특정한 답을 보여줍니다
선택한거에 따라다른 죽음이 있죠협박일 수도
기존의 살인일 수도있죠
거기 숫자들을조합해보면뭔가 의미가
있을 수도 있고요
차일즈 씨?
차일즈 씨
전화에요
차일즈 형삽니다아니, 너 아니지
베스는 죽었어, 아닌가?
나한테 원하는게 뭐야?
날 죽일 수도 있었잖아근데 이렇게 있네
넌 그런 느낌 없었어?
뭐?
우리가 이어져있다는거
어, 그거 내가니 간에다철봉 꽂아준거 말이야?
그건 좀 어때?
내가 너 좀알아야겠거든
다시 한번 만나지
난 니 이름도 모르잖아
나도 너 이름 모르거든
헬레나야
성은 뭐야?니가 지금은
이 짓을 하고 있지만
그게 얼마나 갈까..
진짜 경찰이 날 찾으면?
넌 나야, 난 너고우리 둘다
피해자고 경찰이지
그래, 우리 둘다한테안좋을 수도 있지
그러니 나한테 와의논해보지
내가 벌써 위치는보내놨어
이봐, 이리와
숫자들 말야주소들이야
좋아17은 채석장 번지고
거기서 피해자가 발견됐지그래, 거기 셋방
총격 현장
꼬마의 집
거기에 경찰서까지..
우리가 들렸던 곳들이야
하나만 빼고.. 1024GPS에는 그 번지수로딱 하나의 주소가 나와
꼬마 집에서 10분 거리야레이크포인트 거리
아니, 내가 거기 알아
주변에 불법거주자들이아주 많지
가서 확인해보자고잠깐만비상 전술팀을
기다리게, 어?
저격이 있을 가능성이 있으니자네들 들어가기 전에
먼저 훑어보도록 하게
알겠지?예
저기, 걱정마가보자고
저 이쪽에주차해뒀는데요
아니지 아니지어제 밤부터는우리 뭉치는거야
어서타
와우, 베스!
밤에 힘드셨어요?
그러시다면야
나가요
뭐?
누구 또 등에 표적 붙어있단느낌 드시는 분 없어요?
전부 이상없다알았다, 좋아
제가 여러분들 더 가까이보시도록 데려다 드리죠
분명히 좋아하실겁니다
이쪽이요, 형사님들
수술을더 한것 같네
오래지 않아또 피를 흘리겠어
이런 젠장할
종이접기에서랑같은 그림들이야
이 여자가연쇄 살인범이라고 했던가?
피해자는 하나일지도
우리 신원미상 양..계속 계속해서 그렸네
어쩜 그림실력이삼학년 수준이던가요
그 여자일까?
아님 다음 희생자일까?
다음 희생자요
차일즈 형삽니다
안녕, 나야
폴이라고아
안녕, 폴너 좀 어때?
음. 좋지 않아. 얻어맞았거든뭐야?!
어떻게 된건데?
어, 와서 나 좀데리고 나가줘
범인은 우릴 여기로안내했어
우리가 봐주길바랬던거지
어쩌면 쓸데없는 짓인지도요시간만 버린거죠
아니야
범인한텐이유가 있어
됐다. 감식반이맡도록 해주자고
너 저녁약속없기를 바랄께
네, 바로 쫓아갈께요
내 상상인건가..
아님 코시마가 너보다가슴이 더 큰거야?
키아라랑 오늘 저녁하기로한거 갈 방법이 없단 말이야저, 너 가야되잖아
못가아트하고 부터있어야되고
또 그 개년은내 머리 위에 있단말이야
그년을 키아라한테바로 안내하게 될지도 몰라
알긴 하는데, S 부인은최후통첩을 한거거든너랑 완전히 끊어 버릴꺼야
여기 곤란한 상태라고, 피
그래, 네 본적이 거기지
나한테 하나정말 멍청한 생각이 있는데
어, 좋아
내가 동시에 두군데있어야 되잖아, 그치?그래
머, 누군가 그럴 수 있다면그건 우리지
너 진짜제정신이야?!
그래, 갑자기 그러네
무슨 일 있어?걔 괜찮아?
그래, 괜찮어잘있어
괜찮게 들리지는 않는데사라가 자기 딸 때문에
네 도움이 필요해
난 그 그림들범죄 심리학하는 애한테 보낼께
실종자 중에서는우리 피해자가 안나오나?
동네엔 없어그럼, 범위를 넓혀야지
얼마나요?
북미 전체
와우, 또 바꼈네요
예?
옷차림 전체가
깔끔해지셨다고요
좋아 보이네요
지금은 그럴 때가아니다, 라지
아, 죄송해요
얘들아
이건 또 뭐야 뭐야?
누군가는 재미 좀봤다니 다행이네
매기 첸?
미안한데, 걔 나보고자기 흉내를 내란거네
거의 일 년 동안만나지 못한자기 딸 앞에서 말이야?
열 달이야
최악의 육아법이네필릭스내 말은
애가 불쌍하다고
너가 지금 상황을이해하지 못하나 본데
사라가 오늘 밤 못가면키아라를 영영
못데려 올 수도 있어
미안해, 하지만이런 부탁이라면
어쩜 그 아이한테는
수양엄마랑있는게 더 낫겠다이보세요!
사라는 밖에서복제 살인마하고
생쥐와 고양이 놀이하면서목숨을 걸고 있는데
그렇게 네 아이들은고아가 되진 않을텐데걔는 그때문에 자기 아이를
잃어도 된다는거야?
그래
여기가 네가 나설 때인거같은데, 언니야
머, 내가 "철목련"에서*Steel Magnolias:연극,영화
어넬 역을 하긴 했었지
진짜로?
으흠글렌데일 지역 극장에서
어넬, 어넬.. 세상에나!
데릴 해나가 했던 역?
그래
배역 최악이네실제로 연기 아주 좋았거든
필릭스
내 말 믿어사라한테 해될 거 없어
평가도 대단했다고
전체 주민들한텐..그랬겠지
스페인에 비는 대부분평지에 내린다
(발음 연습용 문장)
됐다, 일라이자이런 젠장할
우리 지금 "피그말리온"에완전 반대되는게 필요하거든
범죄 심리하는 애말로는
성서에 대해엉망이던 아니던
여성 위에 여성을 놓은건개인적인 일이라는거레첫번째 아니면
열다섯 번째 살인이고
예, 아니그거 말되네요
그래서 피해자로돌아가서
누구였다가 죽은거지봐야지
뭔가 나와야되는데
그렇게되면, 알지?
예, 바로 갈께요
제일 안좋은 옷이 이거야?
그래, 미안하다친구야내가 중고 물품은
안사거든
아니, 아니, 이런, 아냐"친구야"가 아니라고
알겠어?좀 더 그러니까 음
"짜샤" 같이하라고
"짜샤"그래
안녕, "짜샤"
그래, 그게 낫다근데..
봐바, 넌 S 부인을꼭 거쳐야만 될꺼라고거기서는 진짜 따분한 역사가
있는걸로 연기해야만돼, 알겠지?
그러니까, 근본적으로말을 하지 않는다고
이 셔츠완전 틀려먹었다
이봐! 이봐 이봐!
"이봐"가 아니지!넌 펑크족이야해봐
어이!
차일즈 형삽니다
손님이 찾아왔어요
저기 저기 저기여기는 뭐하러 온거야?네가 데려다 달랬잖아
무슨 일이야?너 괜찮아?
어, 그래괜찮아 정말이야목소린 아니던데
전혀 아니야
보긴 괜찮네
가자나 일찍 나왔어
네가 원하는데로 하자좋지?아니 아니 아니. 폴, 나 못가!
폴!
여기 아무일 없는거지?
얘가 아무일 없는것처럼보이세요?!
알았네, 진정하게
복귀한 첫날인데얻어맞았어요?떠나고 싶어하는 맘
알겠네요
자네무슨 소릴 하는건가?
아니 아니 아니. 폴, 부탁이야아트? 알아서 할께요
정말?
난 뭐하러 온거야?
미안해내가 좀 민감했어
말 그대로 "어서와서 데려가줘"라고 한건 아니야
그럼 무슨 얘기였는데?
왜냐면, 진짜너 요즘 들어완전히 다른 사람 같거든
미안해, 이 사건 때문이야미친년 때문에
속이 상했거든그래서 데려다 달라고했던거야
나도 번거롭다고말한건 아니야
저기, 우리 둘이서함께 시간 좀 보내야겠다
우리한테 갑자기 무슨일이벌어진건지 알아보자고왜나면 이런거 대부분
나 좋아하거든
아주 많이
폴
생각해봐
그러니까
베스가 쏜 여자하고헬레나하고 연결되있어
완전 끝내주네
그래, 베스가 매기 첸을쏜건 이유가 있었어
그애 우리한테는이런 얘기 전혀 안했는데
그래, 자기 파트너한테도전혀 얘기 안했더라
나 이짓 계속 못하겠어코지마헬레나가 왔었어
베스로 분장하고
내가 만나주지않으면
우리 둘을 폭로시키겠데혼자오레오, 이런
안좋은 생각인데
맞아, 걘 우리가연결되어있다고 생각해그런거?
그래우리 복제인간이거든
그렇지, 경찰들은뭘 알아냈어?
애가 교회에 미쳤다는거쯧
개인적이란거혼자 일하고,
아마 아이때 학대를 당했다는거
좋아, 그래
the fish그 물고기는기독교인을 나타내
또, 무기에 새겨진건?
개인적인 성전이지대단하다
그런거야?
그게 말이지매기 첸한테
이 낙인 있는걸 봤을때내가 생각한건얘는 혼자 싸우는
전사가 아니란거야
극도의창조론 지지자들에겐
우리가협오스러워 보이겠지그게, 신의 자식이 아니면
그건, 사탄의 자식란 식이지
그래서 우릴 싫어하고걘 우릴 죽이는거네
자기도 우리랑 동질성을가졌는데도?머 그래도 니가 망가진체
학대당하고 고립된 사람으로
신앙에 속하라강요당한다면또 네가 신뢰하는
누군가
신의 눈으로 봤을때 그것이너 자신이 보상받을 길이라고
말해준다면, 내 얘긴..그래, 나라도
화난 천사가 되겠지
좋아, 알았어고마워
나한태 얘기하고싶은거 뭐 없어?
폴 말이에요?
아니에요, 그이는 제가손가락만 까딱해도 되요그 친구 무슨 얘기한거야
떠난다고?
너 이제 막 돌아왔잖아베스
아니에요, 그이는 자기가무슨 얘기한지도 몰라요
지금은 일들이꼬여있어서 그래요
그래그 얘긴 들었지
그래도 우린 그런거 여기끌고오진 않거든, 알았어?알아요
엄청 쪽팔리네요
걱정마세요다신 없을 꺼에요
난 너희 둘이끝내기로 한걸로 알았는데
예, 그래요근데, 지금은잘해보려고
하고 있어요
그런게 어떤지아시잖아요
그렇지
그럼 본 궤도로돌아가지
살인범 말야
그 년이랑 아주 가까이서한판 했잖아
다른 건 눈치 못챘어?
뭔가 말했다던가?그 년이 무슨 말을
했으면
저도 여자란걸알았을꺼에요
그래, 난 벡위드랑확인해도록 할께
피해자에 대해서작업을 하고 있으니까
조만간 안면 재구성이끝날꺼야
잘됐네요
차일즈 형삽니다
지금 거기 일이 너한테불편하게 돌아갈텐데
헬레나너 뭐 잊어버렸던데
니 친구 매기
아, 너형편없는 형사구나
베스는그걸 알아냈었지
그게, 베스가 쏜거지나 아니거든
네가 복수를쫓고 있다면..
복수에 대한게 아니야
너에 대한거지
맞아, 우리한텐연결점이 있지
그거 얘기 해주고싶은거야?만나서
내 초대장 갔거든
제 이름은베스 차일즈 형삽니다
제가 마가렛 첸을살해했습니다
사고가 아니였죠
제가 고의로죽인겁니다
한대 빨았더니숨이 가쁘네아니, 아니지
사라는 담배 안피거든
좋아막이 열릴 시간이야
그냥 그것만 기억해
모욕하는게 인사야그래도 성질 내지는
않도록 해봐, 알았지?
잠깐. 음, 고마워요
좋아
구부정하게구부정하게 해
닥쳐
이제 이해했구나
어-어이, S 아줌마!
오늘은 멋드러진 새 재규어는안타고 왔냐, 그래서?
정비소에요
제 딸 보게 해주실꺼에요아님 뭐에요?
뜸들여서 뭐하려고?
내가 도와줄 거라도?
너 여자랑 싸워봤었지?그야 경우에 따라
일이야 재미로 말야?
저기, 미치면 강해진다고다들 그러잖아
그래도 여자는외모도 다르고
싸움도 다르고냄새도 다르지
이 여잔훈련받은 저격수야
그래도 베스는남자라고 생각했지뭔가 걸리지 않아?
요즘 말이야그애 속에 다른 뭔가
걸리는게 있는느낌이 들거든
알잖아, 민간인을 쏜건떨쳐내기 힘들어너무 빨리
돌아온건가보지
그렇다고 해도모르겠어어쨌거나
얘 어디갔지?
자기 남자친구랑 일보고있는지도 모르지, 그찮아?
그래, 그럴지도
뭐야?아니야
이제 또 뭔데안보이는 잉크?
자리 좀 봐줘, 엔지나도 같이가야 되지
않을까?
이것봐, 아트뭔데?
알게되면 말해줄께
키아라엄마가 기다리신다
서둘러라, 얘야어서
여기야. 봐라엄마 왔잖니
물지 않는단다얘야
어이, 지금 부끄럼 타는거니아님 뭘까?
그거 나 주려고?
어디 좀 볼까?
부억에서 차나한잔 하시죠, 예?
한번 안아볼까?
미안한다우리가 한동안
못 봤었잖니하지만 모든게 바껴서
언제나서로 볼 수 있을까?
아줌마우리 엄마 아니에요
바보같긴
당연히 내가 엄마잖니
내가 또 누구겠어?
엄마랑 똑같이생긴거 뿐이에요
여전히 나란다키아라
저 부를때뭐라고 하세요?
원숭이다른건요?
원숭이하고.. 음?
예쁜이?
우리 엄마 어딨어요?
아트, 만약 이거들으시거든요
시체를 찾으신거에요
그건 베스가 아니에요저에요
제 이름은사라 매닝이고..
당신은 이 모든 일을밝혀내실 수 있다고
제가 믿는거의 유일한 사람이에요
키아라, 당장은 너희 엄마가여기 올 수가 없었어
왜요?
경찰이에요!안에 계세요!
왜냐면 엄마는 바로 지금어딘가에서
굉장히 용감한 일을하고 계시거든모두가 안심할 수 있도록
하고 계셔
그래야 둘이함께 있을 수 있잖니
난 무기 없어
뒤로 돌아
뒤로 돌아! 확실히
꿇어
어떻게 하는지는알겠지
이럴 필요 없잖아무릎 꿇어
넌 다른 것들이랑다르구나
그래, 그렇지
얘기하고 싶뎄지?한번 해보자
나 죽어가나봐
그래내가 지켜봐주지
넌 어디서 왔지?
어디선가 튀어 나왔지
넌 어디서 왔어?
신이 보내셨지
올커니너도 모른단거네넌 신을 몰라
이런 신?
니 친구 매기 첸에찍혀있던 낙인?
매기는 널 만드는걸도왔었지
그리곤 빛을 봤고
그래서 우리 쪽으로온거야
베스는 우릴 보호하려고그 여잘 죽인거네
널 구해줄 수 있어
그렇겠지우린 연결되 있으니까난 네 안에
빛을 볼 수 있어
우리 전부는 안에하나의 빛이 있거든
아니야!
아... 아니야!
다른 것들은인간의 신의 형상따른
조악한 복제품일 뿐이야
넌 아니란거야?
넌 특별해?
너한테 니가 원본이라고그랬군, 아니야?
너희쪽 사람들!
그들이 말한건사실이 아니야!
우린 유전적으로 동일해
내가 널 구해줄께너, 나, 베스
니가 죽인 독일 애도!
우린 전부 똑같이만들어 졌다고
너보고 다르다고 했던게누구던지놈들이 우릴 미워하는 만큼
너도 미워하는거야
니가 틀렸어
무슨일이 있었던거야헬레나?
물러서!
너 느껴지니?
베스!
베스너 안에 있어?
도망가!
느껴지지 않아?
여기 아무도 없어요!너가 있지
뭐야?
베스!
니가 죽인 여자의아파트에?
젠장 너 정신이있는거야?
어떻게 앨리슨 고모가되는거에요?
우리 엄마는자매가 하나도 없는데요우리 엄마는
엄마도 없어요
그게, 많이 복잡하단다
그래도, 키아라너한텐 미안하지만
그래도 니가비밀로 해주는게정말로 중요해
알았지?
약속?
자러가야겠다키아라 얘야
올라가자,잠옷 챙기고
새끼 손가락
안녕, 엄마
얼른가
전부 고마워요머, 네가 약속을 지켰잖니
나타났잖아
키아라 말이에요
애가 잘있잖아요그게, 어, 덕분에요
사라
내가 그냥, 어..
내가 그냥 이 문제에 대해솔직히 말하는게 익숙하지 않아서
음, 저 다시 오면좋겠어요
빠를 수록요늦는거 보단 낫죠
반대하진 않을께그래도 천천히 하자꾸나
그럼, 제가내일 들려서
학교에서 집까지같이 걸을께요
바로 집으로요
그렇다면야, 알았다
이런, 비둘기가 풀려났네
바로 모퉁이에세계 평화가 올꺼야
어여 꺼져버려
머, 넌 놀랍지않나보네통과했잖아!
너가 S 부인 머리를삼촌쪽으로 돌린거야, 음화!
머, 그런거지
어-어
키아라가바로 알아보더라
뭐
이런, 젠장!
내가 이해가안가거든나한텐 도대체 말도
안되는 일이야
왜 자네가 매기 첸집에 갔는지
설명이나 해봐
말씀 드렸듯이요머리 좀 비우려고
산책 좀 하다가요무심코 간거에요그냥 무심코 갔다고?
네
"예"인가 "아니"인가..매기 첸 총격하고
신원미상자 살인사건 사이에연결점이 있는건가?없어요
저기, 니가 회의를요청했잖아, 베스
그럼 우리가여기서 뭐하는거야?
첸 사건 이후에 전,제 자신이할 수 있다는걸 보여주려고 돌아왔어요
근데 누구한테도 뭐하나도잘 못하고 있죠. 그래서..
빠질께요
우리가 너한테그렇게나 전부 해줬는데도?
예, 그 점 감사드려요그래도..근데 나가겠다
왜지?
너 뭔가 있는거야?!
빠져나가는건해답이 아니네, 차일즈
이러면 어떻게 되죠?
이런거 말입니다?
I saw a girl kill herself.
And she looked exactly like me.
Elizabeth Childs. To find out who she is
or to rob the rest of her shit?
Beth is a cop. I'm a cop.
Who the hell is Maggie Chen?
That's the woman Beth shot.
The only way you willregain custody of Kira
- is to show me you can be still.- We're clones.
We're someone's experimentand they're killing us off!
The German's dead.
Someone shot her right in front of me!
You need to get rid of the body.
Beth's partner found the German...
or at least part of her.
If the body matches me, the cops will see
a mugshot of somebody who looks like Beth,only it's yours truly and I'm
already supposed to be dead.
Beth had a substantial sum,
a fund she used to buy
information we couldn't get officially.The fund was how I could contribute.
The killer contacted Art.
He's already at the scenewhere Katja was shot.
That was in the sniper's nest.
We got a live one. Phonecalls, leaving clues.
"I am fearfully and wonderfully made."
I'm okay! Go after him, go!
Oh!
I'm not Beth!
"I'm not Beth".
Shh.
Why would one of us be killing us?
What is wrong with her?Bad breath. Batshit crazy.
Does she know about me, about my kids?
How do you know you didn't justbring her right to my doorstep?
Because she's impaled withrebar and I wouldn't do that.
I have been living this nightmare
much longer than you have, Sarah.
I explained I have a family to protect.
I do what I can.
Right, you provide financially.
Yeah, so you wanted thatmoney Beth was holding.
Your self defense fund.
You're right, I was going to steal it
and run, but I can't do that,
because I have a family, too, Alison,
my daughter.
Your daughter?
Yeah. Her name's Kira
and I'm meant to be seeing her today,
but there's this killer up my arse, so.
Wait, is she your biological child
or adopted, like mine?
Mine. Why?
Don't you think you should'vetold us about that before?
Why would I do that?
I'm telling you now because we have to
deal with this, yeah?
Beth was on this killer'shit list and, now, I am.
Yeah? What am I supposed to do about it?
How can I help?
Be available.
I may need you, somehow.
Wow, rich, man.
This looks like a new blade inset
in a much older handle,
so the fish is a bitch,semiotically speaking,
like a universal waybacksymbol of fecundity.
But these wings, though, they're...
Seriously, what is she on about?
Quiet. She's just weird.
Sorry. Sorry sorry sorry.
Okay, going on a tangent there.
If she's not dead,
we need to find her,find out what she knows.
Are you mad?
She's a homicidal maniac.
Yeah, but we need to findout who she is, Sarah.
She's... she's she found us.
She's got answers.
The only way I'm going to do that is
go back to being a cop.
No.
No way. You're notgoing back to being Beth.
Impersonating a dead officer,that's like a whole new crime.
I think I'm safest with thecops, to be honest with you.
Did that actually justcome out of your mouth?
Look, Art's already looking for the killer.
I shadow him as Beth,
I let them figure outwhat's happened to her,
and then, when I find that out,
I can jump off and deal.
"Deal"?
I'm beginning to realize crazy's genetic.
Well, yeah, bad brain chemistry
can be genetic,
but environment...that's individual, right?
I mean, that's the whole
nature/nurture question right there.
Okay, let's talk nature.
Out of 9, so far,
one's a psycho who killed 4 others,
one committed suicide,
one is a bloody soccer mum,
and then, there's you.
My crazy sister is sane, by comparison.
Thanks, Fe.
I think this might help us figure out
where she's coming from,so I'll look into it.
Ah, police business.
- Art's got a lead.- Okay.
Hey, you didn't show this to Alison,
by any chance, did you?
Are you joking? She'd crap her lululemons.
I've got Alison on standby.
Make sure Gemma wears her seatbelt!
You're sending the kids to your parentson a school morning.
Well, they're staying the night.
That's not an answer.
Well, you didn't pose it asa question, did you, Donnie?
Okay. Why?
Why did you cancel all their activities?
I just wanted some time to myself.
You have your usual Thursday-nightdrinks with clients, right?Yes.
So I'll see you when you come
crashing in at 3:00 am, normal time.
I don't crash in.
One time.
Oh, crap.
Sorry.
I'm jumpy, too.
How's your head?
Probably about the same as yours.
It's a good day to be alive, Beth.
My kids thank you.
Hell, even my ex thanks you.
Yeah, don't mention it.
I didn't. They did it.
I got a present for you.
Our killer made a pit-stop.
That's his bike.
They got him?
No, but we got a witness.
Just follow the bloody brick road.
Hey, there he is, our walking wounded.
You all good, Art?
- Yeah.- Yeah? Hey, glad you're okay.
We're going to get thisguy. Don't worry, all right?So your guy wore gloves. No prints.
But he's not exactly covering his tracks.
Go take a look.
Self-surgery.
Guy's what, military?
Looks like it's gotta hurt.
Oh, the witness is ready.
Art, you want to take him?
No.
Come on.
I slept through the whole thing.
I can't believe it.
Trevor came into my room.
It was dark
and he was all wet
with blood.
He said it was an angry angel.
Hey, Trevor.
Can you tell me what theangry angel looked like?
The person in your bathroom was a woman?
Is that possible?
Let me talk to him.
Yeah, sure.
It's okay, darling.
I'm not her.
She said you would come.
Pick a color.
Red.
That one.
Wait wait wait. Let me see that.
- Can I keep this?- Yes.
What you got there?
Souvenir.
What the hell?
Hey, can you bag this?
It's okay, sweetie. It's okay.
Yes, once again, 8:00, before her bedtime.
Is that my mum?
No, hon.
Did you just tell her it wasn't me?
Sarah, why are you calling?
If you don't show, after allthis anticipation, I will...
Just making sure we're still on.
Well, we are, at this end.
Yeah, I'll be there.
Can I talk to her?
You can talk to her tonight.
If you let her down,
that's it, I won't let you see her again.
I said I'll be there.
So you all have copiesof the fortune teller.
Eyewitness says we got it wrong...
Jane Doe's killer isfemale, about Beth's size.
As for the Jane Doe,
it isn't easy, reconstructing a skull
that's gone through a gravel crusher, but,
we do have cause of death.
This hole, .223-caliber.
So, we have a long-range,high-powered weapon.
Name me one homicide
ever pinned on a female sniper.
How's that profile?
Female killers tend to sufferfrom chronic detachment.
Isolation breeds sociopaths.
This psalm, "fearfullyand wonderfully made"...
she's a religious fanatic.
The stick figures, the doll's head,
the fortune teller...
early-childhood development issues?
Could be extreme abuse.
Yes, but he's also careful, in her way.
No prints on any of this, so far.
And the DNA evidence?
On rush, but we're still a week away
from knowing if they match anyone on file.
Nothing on Jane Doe's prints?
Her hand didn't give us a match?
No. No, they did not.Look, the bottom line is
we are chasing a calculated
female killer who loves playing games.
Like these fortune tellers.
Angie.
Certain choices give certain answers.
Every choice is a different death.
Could be threats, could be existing kills.
They might mean something,
when combined with the numbers.
Childs?
Childs.
Call for you.
Detective Childs.
No, you're not.
Beth is dead, isn't she?
What do you want from me?
You could've killed me, but here we are.
You didn't feel it?
What?
We have a connection.
Uh, you mean when I stuck
that piece of rebar in your liver?
How's that going?
I need to know who you are.
Let's meet again.
I never got your name.
I never got yours.
Helena.
And last name?
You're doing all this work,
but how long can that last,
when the real police find me?
You are me, I'm you,
we're both the victim and the cop.
Yeah, that would be bad for both of us.
So come see me, discuss.
I already gave you directions.
Hey, c'mere.
The numbers, they're addresses.
Okay, 17 is the street number of the quarrywhere we found Jane Doe.
Yeah. Rooming house,
shooting scene,
the kid's house,
even the precinct...
everywhere we've been.
Except one... 1024. GPS gives one address
with that street number,
10 minutes from the kid'shouse, Lakepoint Road.
No, I know that place.
A lot of squatters around there.
- Let's check it out.- Hold it.
Wait for emergency tactical, huh?
This is a probable sniper,
so let them sweep it,first, before you go in.
- Got it?- Yeah.
Hey, don't worry. Let's do this.
I'm parked over here, so.
No no no no no. After last night,we stick together. Come on.
Whoa, Beth!
Rough night?
Okeydoke, then.
Out.
What?
Anybody else feel like theyhave a target on their back?
- All clear.- Copy. Okay,
I'll take you guys in for a closer look.
You're going to love it.
Over here, detectives.
Looks like more self-surgery.
Can't be long 'til she bleeds out.
Ho-ly shit.
It's the same figuresas the fortune teller.
She saying she's a serial killer?
Could be her single victim,
our Jane Doe, over and over again.
Or she just draws like a third-grader.
This her?
Or her next victim?
Next victim.
Detective Childs.
Hey, it's me.
- Paul?- Oh.
Hello, Paul.
How are you doing?
- Mm, not too good. I got beat up.- What?!
What happened?
Oh, please come get me outta here.
She led us here.
She wanted us to see this.
May be a wild goose chase,
- wasting our time.- No.
She had a reason.
Okay, let's let forensics have this.
I hope you don't have dinner plans.
Yeah, I'll be right with you.
Is it my imagination,
or does Cosima havebigger breasts than you?
There's no way I can makedinner with Kira tonight.
Well, you've got to.
I can't. I'm stuck with Art
and this bitch is right on top of me.
I could lead her straight to Kira.
I know, but Mrs S gave you an ultimatum.
She's going to cut you off.
Rock and a hard place, here, Fe.Yeah, your permanent address.
I do have one really idiotic idea.
Oh, good.
I need to be in two places at once, yeah?
Yeah.
Well, if anybody can do that, we can.
Are you effing serious?!
Yeah, suddenly, I am.
What happened? Is she okay?
Yeah, she's okay. She's fine.
That doesn't sound okay.
Sarah needs your help with her daughter.
I'll get the drawings outto my criminal-psych guy.
Where's missing persons on our Jane Doe?
Nothing local.
Well, widen the net.
How wide?
North America.
Whoa, quick change.
Huh?
Your whole look,
it's cleaned right up.
Looks way better.
Keep it in your pants, Raj.
Uh, sorry.
Guys,
what the hell?
Nice to know someone's having fun.
Maggie Chen?
I'm sorry, but she wants me
to impersonate her,in front of her own daughter,
who she hasn't seen in almost a year?
10 months.
This is terrible parenting, Felix.
I mean, that poor child.
I don't think you understandthe situation here.
If Sarah misses tonight,
then she may never get Kira back.
I'm sorry, but a request like this?
Maybe the child is better off
with your foster mother.
Excuse me?
Sarah is out there, risking her life,
playing cat-and-mousewith killer clone,
so that your kids don't end up orphans,and you think that she should
lose her child for that?
Yeah.
I think you need to step up, here, sister.
Well, I did just play Annelle
in "Steel Magnolias".
Seriously?
Mm-hmm. Glendale community theatre.
Annelle, Annelle... oh, my God!
The Daryl Hannah part?
Yeah.
Terrible casting.
It was actually very good acting, Felix.
Trust me, Sarah's no stretch.
I got great reviews.
From the whole neighborhood, I'm sure.
Ahem.
The rain in Spain
falls mainly on the plain.
Okay, Eliza. Holy shit.
We need to pull a fullreverse "Pygmalion" here.
My crime-psych guy says
biblically messed up or not,
woman-on-woman meansits got to be personal,
whether it's her first or 15th kill.
Yeah, no, that makes sense.
So we're back to Jane Doeand who she was to Jane death.
Something's gotta give.
When it does, you know?
Yeah. Right behind ya.
Ahem.
These are your worst clothes?
Well, I'm sorry, mate,
but I don't shop secondhand.
No, no, my God, no. It's not "mate",
all right? It's more like, um,
it's like "might".
- "Might".- Yeah.
'Ello, "might".
Yeah, that's better. But,
look, you're going tohave to get past Mrs S,
so you really got to play thedreary history there, you know?
I mean, you basically won't talk.
This shirt is all wrong.
Hey! Hey hey!
Not "hey"! You're a punk.
Be one.
Oi!
Detective Childs.
There's a visitor for you.
Hey hey hey. What are you doing here?
You said come get you.
What happened? Are you okay?
Yeah. Yeah, no, I'm fine. Really.
You didn't sound fine and you don't
look fine.
Come on, I took the rest of the day off.
Whatever you need, okay?
- No no no. No. Paul, I can't!- Paul!
Everything all right here?
Does she seem all right to you?!
Okay. Take it easy.
First day back, she gets beat up?
No wonder she wants to leave.
Boy, what the hell are you talking about?No no no no. Paul, please. Art? I got this.
Do you?
What am I doing here?
Sorry, I overreacted.
I didn't mean literally"come get me this second".
Then what did you mean?
Because, seriously, you're like
a completely different person, these days.
Sorry, it's this case. It's a bitch.
I got upset, so I asked you to come get me.
I didn't say I minded.
Look, we need to spend some time together,
figure out what's suddenly going on with us
because most of it, I like,
a lot.
Paul.
Think about it.
So,
the woman Beth shot andHelena are connected.
Holy watershed.
Okay, Beth probably shotMaggie Chen on purpose.
She never told us anything about this.
Yeah, she never told her partner, either.
I can't keep doing this, Cosima.
Helena was here. She was Beth.
She's going to get us both busted,unless I meet her, alone.
Oh, my God. Bad idea.
Yeah, she thinks we have a connection.
Do you?
Yeah, we're clones.
Right. So what do the cops know?
She's a churchy psychopath. Duh.
It's personal.
She's a loner, probably abused as a child.
Okay, so,
the fish
reads Christian
and, crafted onto a weapon?
A personal crusade.
Great. Is that it?
You know, when I'm seeing this
branded onto Maggie Chen, I'm thinking that
she's not a lone warrior.
To extreme creationist types,
we would be abominations.
Like, not God's children,but, but, Satan's.
So they hate us and she's killing us,
even though she's identical to us?
Well, but if you were amessed-up, abused lonerwhose faith compelled you
to belong and somebody that you trustedtold you that this was
the way to redeem yourself
in the eyes of God, I mean...
Yeah, I might become an angry angel, too.
Okay, got it. Thanks.
Something you want to tell me?
About Paul?
No. I've got him wrappedaround my little finger.
What's he talking about, leaving?
We just got you back, Beth.
No, he doesn't knowwhat he's talking about.
Things are just messy right now.
Yeah, I heard that.
But we don't bring thatshit in here, right?
I know.
It's so frickin' embarrassing.
Don't worry. It won't happen again.
I thought you two were calling it quits.
Yeah, we were, but, now,
we're trying to work it out.
You know how things go.
Right.
Let's get back on track.
This killer.
You had a close-quartersrun-in with her.
Did you get anything else?
Something she said?
If she'd said anything,
I would've known she was a woman.
Yeah. I'm going to check with Beckwith.
She's making progress on Jane Doe.
Mm.
She'll have facial reconstruction soon.
Great.
Detective Childs.
Things must be gettinguncomfortable there for you now.
Helena,
you forgot something. Your friend Maggie.
Oh, you're a terrible detective.
Beth figured that out.
Well, Beth shot her, not me,if it's revenge you're after.
It's not about revenge.
It's about you.
Right, we have a connection.
You want to tell me about that?
In person.
You have my invitation.
My name is Detective Beth Childs.
I murdered Margaret Chen.
It wasn't an accident.
I shot her on purpose.
I'm gasping for a fag.
No, you're not. Sarah never smoked.
Okay, it's curtain time.
So just remember that
an insult is a greeting,
but you're trying not tolose your temper, yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Wait. Um, thanks.
Okay.
Over-slouching.You're over-slouching.
Shut up.
Now you got it.
Oi-oi, Mrs S!
Not driving the nice new Jag today, then?
- It's in the shop.- Mm-hmm.
Are you going to let mesee my daughter, or what?
What are you gaping at?
Something I can do?
You ever fight a woman?
Depends. Business or pleasure?
Look, they do say crazy makes you strong.
But women, they look different,
fight different, smell different.
This woman is a trained sniper.
But Beth taking her for a man,
- that flies with you?- Mm.
This whole time, it feels like she's got
something else chewing on her mind.
You know, a civilianshooting's hard to shake.
Maybe she's back too soon.I don't know if that's even it.
Where is she, anyway?
Could be she's just working itout with her boyfriend, right?
Yeah, could be.
- What?- Nothing.
So what, now, invisible ink?
Mind the store, Angie.
Maybe I should come with.
Come on, Art. What's up?
You'll know when I do.
Kira, your mum's waiting.
Hurry up, love. Come on.
Here she is. Look, she's here.
She won't bite, love.
Oi, are you shy now, or something?
Is that for me?
Can I see it?
How about a cuppa in the kitchen, yeah?
Wow!
Give us a hug?
I'm sorry we haven't
seen each other in a long time,
but we can change all that,
see each other all the time?
You're not my mother.
Silly.
Of course I'm your mum.
Who else would I be?
You just look like her.
It's still me, Kira.
What do you call me?
Monkey.
What else?
Monkey... bum?
Face?
Where's my mum?
Art, if you're hearing this,
you found the body.
It's not Beth. It's me.
My name is Sarah Manning and...
you're about the only person I trust
to figure the whole thing out.
Kira, your mothercouldn't be here right now.
Why?
Police! Stay inside!
Because she is out there, right now,
doing something very brave.
She's making sure everything is safe
so you two can be together.
I'm unarmed.
Turn around.
Turn around! All the way.
Kneel.
I'm guessing you know how.
This isn't necessary. Kneel down.
You're different than the others.
Yeah, I am.
Uh!
You wanted to talk? Let's talk.
I think I'm dying.
Yeah, I think I'll watch.
Where did you come from?
I came out of the woodwork.
God sent me.
Right, so you don't know, either.
You don't know God.
This God?
The one branded on your friend Maggie Chen?
Maggie helped make you.
Then she saw the light
and came to our side.
Beth killed her to protect us.
I can save you.
Right, because we have a connection.
I can see a light in you.
There's a light in all of us.
No!
N... no!
The others,
poor copies of God's image of human beings.
But not you?
You're special?
They told you you werethe original, didn't they?
You people!
It's not true, what they said!
We're genetic identicals.
Let me save you.
You, me, Beth, the German you killed!
We're all made the same.
Whoever told you different
hates you as much as they hate us.
You're wrong.
What happened to you, Helena?
Stay back!
Can you feel it?
Beth!
Beth, are you in there?
Run!
You don't feel it?
- There's no one here!- You're here.
Why?
Beth!
The apartment of the woman you killed?
What the hell are you thinking?
How can you be my auntie Alison?
My mum doesn't have any sisters.
My mum doesn't even have a mum.
Well, it's very complicated.
But, Kira, I'm sorry about this,but it's very important
that you keep this a secret, right?
Promise?
Getting on for bedtime, Kira, love.
Up you go. Get your PJs.
Pinkies.
Bye, mummy.
Scoot.
Thanks for everything.
Well, you kept your word. You showed up.
I mean Kira.
She's well and that's, uh, down to you.
Sarah.
I'm just, uh,
I'm not used to an honestword on the subject.
Um, I'd like to do this again,
sooner, rather than later.
I'm not opposed, long as we take it slowly.
So, I'll be by tomorrow
to walk her home from school.
Straight home.
Well, all right, then.
Well, unleash the doves.
World peace must beright around the corner.
Piss off, you.
Well, aren't you full of surprises.You passed!
You turned S's head for your Uncle. Mwah!
Well, that's something.
Uh-oh.
Kira knew right away.
No.
Oh, shite!
I just don't get it.
It doesn't make any sense to me.
Just explain to us why you were
at the home of Maggie Chen.
Like I said, I was taking a walk
to clear my head. I found myself there.
You just found yourself there? Yeah.
"Yes" or "no"... isthere a connection betweenthe Maggie Chen shooting death
and this Jane Doe homicide?
None.
Well, you called this meeting, Beth.
What the hell are we doing here?
After the Chen thing, I cameback to prove that I could,
but I'm not doing anybody any good, so,
I quit.
After all we've done for you?
Yeah. I appreciate it, but...
But you bail. Why?
What is it with you?!
Walking out's not the answer, Childs.
So how does this go?
Something like this?
What'll they do to me?
This is about Paul, right?
We think Beth was spying on him.
She wasn't messing around, was she?
Maybe it's time to findout where Paul works.
What happened to your scar?
Why were you in my vanity?
- Donnie, what's in the box?!- I don't know who you are.
Sarah, I thought you were dead!
Is someone trying to hurt us?
Why do you ask that?
How could you do that to her?